Hi, my name is Guillermo Gomez, I coach soccer.
Have you ever seen a goalie kick the ball?
Well, he actually bounces on the ground first and then he kicks it far away to his teammates, towards the middle of the soccer field.
That's what you call a goalie drop kick.
o.k.
So today I'm going to be explaining how to do that.
First if all, you know you're the goalie.
You normally want to get comfortable with the ball so what you can do is just take a few bounces on the ball with your hands, so bounce the ball down about two or three times, o.k.
Then you want to put the ball with one hand, right about in the west, in your west area, waist, I'm sorry, in the waist area.
O.k., now put the ball in front of you, o.k. You're going to take about three steps going forward and then you're going to be dropping the ball, o.k.
The ball's going to touch the ground.
And as soon as that ball touches the ground you're going to kick that ball, making your body lean backwards and not forward.
You want to look at the area of the ball, which is basically the lower section of the ball.
That's the area you're going to be kicking and it needs to be right about the middle, o.k.
You want to lock your ankles, that's very important, lock the ankle, point your toes down and kick it with your shoelace.
Alright, so to summarize it, we do it again.
You want to put the ball with one hand, o.k., right about the waist size of the waist elevation or area of your body.
Put the ball in front of you, take about three steps with it, Drop the ball, o.k.
And as soon as the ball touch the ground, o.k., your supporting leg comes right next to it, a little bit behind it, so bring your body back, shoelaces and toes pointing down, kick the ball underneath and send it nice along.
And that's how you can do a drop kick, a goalie drop kick.
So fun out there with your friends while you practice this kick.